Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katrin and we're shoe shopping again.
我是Katrin，我们又来买鞋了。
That's right.
没错。
We are going shoe shopping but this time it's a little bit more complicated because we're
我们要去买鞋，但这次有点复杂，因为我们要
getting women's shoes.
买女鞋。
That's right.
没错。
So there are so many different kinds of women's shoes.
所以女鞋有好多不同的种类。
I'm not even sure I know them all myself but in this intermediate level lesson we're going
我自己都不一定全认识，但在这个中级课程中，我们会
to cover some of the basics for you.
为你介绍一些基本款式。
That's right.
没错。
Before we jump into this dialogue we have a word that we want to preview with you today
在我们进入对话之前，今天有一个词想先预览一下，
and let's take a look at it now on Vocabulary Preview.
现在来看看词汇预览部分。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so we're shopping today for a certain kind of shoe.
好的，今天我们买的是某种特定的鞋。
It's not a sports shoe.
不是运动鞋。
It's a dress shoe.
是正装鞋。
Okay, that kind of doesn't make sense because a dress is a noun.
嗯，这听起来有点奇怪，因为“dress”是名词，
A shoe is a noun and so you want to get a shoe that's a dress?
“shoe”也是名词，所以你要买一双“裙子鞋”？
No.
不是。
A dress shoe is a style of shoe.
“Dress shoe”是一种鞋的风格。
It means shoes that you wear when you're wearing fancy clothes.
意思是当你穿正式衣服时穿的鞋。
So it's kind of like a formal shoe.
所以有点像正式鞋。
A dress shoe is a type of shoe that would go well with a dress.
“Dress shoe”是一种和裙子搭配的鞋。
That's right, not sneakers.
没错，不是运动鞋。
But don't be fooled.
但别搞错了。
This is not about dresses because men can wear dress shoes too.
这不是指裙子，因为男人也可以穿正装鞋。
That's right.
没错。
It means shoes you would wear to a conference or to a wedding or to church.
意思是你会穿去开会、婚礼或教堂的鞋。
So these are things that are a little bit fancier than everyday shoes.
所以这些比日常鞋更讲究一些。
Okay, awesome.
好的，太棒了。
So we're shopping for a dress shoe and there are so many types and styles of shoes for
所以我们在买正装鞋，女鞋有这么多类型和款式，
women so why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a
不如我们先听一遍对话，一会儿再回来。
second.
好的。
Hi, excuse me sir.
嗨，打扰一下，先生。
I'm looking for a dress shoe.
我在找正装鞋。
My usual pair that I've had for years have finally been stretched out of shape.
我穿了好几年的那双鞋终于变形了。
They don't provide any support anymore.
它们不再提供任何支撑了。
Sure, what kind of shoe are you looking for?
当然，您在找什么样的鞋？
We've got strappy sandals, sleek high heels, edgy pumps.
我们有带子凉鞋、时尚高跟鞋、前卫浅口鞋。
If you're looking for something a little more practical, we've got Mary Janes, ballerinas.
如果您想要更实用的，我们有玛丽珍鞋、芭蕾平底鞋。
Show me some classic high heels please.
请给我看一些经典高跟鞋。
Okay, right this way.
好的，这边请。
What color did you have in mind?
您想要什么颜色？
Black, classic.
黑色，经典款。
Of course.
当然。
We've got this style here that is very popular.
我们这里有这款，非常受欢迎。
Because it's an open toe shoe, you can wear it any time of the year.
因为是露趾鞋，一年四季都能穿。
It'll look great on everyone.
谁穿都好看。
Um, too shiny.
嗯，太亮了。
And I wear pantyhose with my shoes so let's look for a closed toe shoe.
而且我穿鞋会配连裤袜，所以还是看闭趾鞋吧。
Okay, these are a very nice pair of leather shoes with a two inch heel so they are very
好的，这双皮鞋很不错，有两英寸的跟，所以非常
comfortable.
舒适。
I don't like the pointed toes.
我不喜欢尖头。
Let me take a look at what else you have.
让我看看你们还有什么别的。
Too high.
太高了。
That one looks like the back would cut into my heel.
那双看起来后跟会割到我的脚后跟。
I have a high instep so I doubt that one would fit properly.
我脚背高，所以我觉得那双肯定不合脚。
I don't want bows.
我不想要蝴蝶结。
I find slingbacks very uncomfortable.
我觉得后空凉鞋很不舒服。
Those might as well be stilettos.
那些跟细高跟差不多。
Too modern.
太现代了。
Ah, finally!
啊，终于找到了！
This is what I'm looking for.
这就是我要找的。
What size?
什么尺码？
Seven and a half.
七码半。
Here we are.
给您。
How does it fit?
合脚吗？
Mmm, not good.
嗯，不太好。
They're too tight.
太紧了。
The length is right but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching my toes.
长度合适，但鞋太窄了，夹我的脚趾。
And there'd be no room for my insoles.
而且也没地方放我的鞋垫。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I don't think I have the patience for this today.
我觉得我今天没耐心了。
They just don't make shoes like they used to.
现在的鞋就是不如以前做得好。
I'll come back another time.
我改天再来。
Have a nice day, ma'am.
祝您愉快，女士。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a lot of shoe styles as you noticed, a lot of them are very, I don't know, I don't
所以很多鞋的款式，就像你注意到的，很多都非常，我不知道，我甚至
even know what they are.
不知道它们是什么。
So why don't we try and explain them now on Language Takeaway.
那我们不如现在就在“语言小课堂”里解释一下它们吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言小课堂。
So the first kind of shoe we've got here is very popular in the summer.
我们这里第一种鞋在夏天非常流行。
It's called a strappy sandal.
它叫做绑带凉鞋。
A strappy sandal.
绑带凉鞋。
So we know what a sandal is.
我们都知道凉鞋是什么。
It's kind of like what you wear to the beach.
就是那种去海滩穿的东西。
It's a shoe that doesn't really cover your whole foot, just the bottom.
这种鞋不会完全包住整只脚，只包住脚底。
It's very open.
它非常开放。
And well, what about strappy?
那“绑带”是什么意思呢？
Strappy comes from the word strap.
“绑带”这个词来自“带子”。
So strap is like a thin piece of fabric or leather that connects other pieces.
带子就是一块连接其他部分的薄布料或皮革。
And so a strappy sandal means that it's got many of these different little straps on it,
所以绑带凉鞋意味着它上面有很多这样的小带子。
many lines everywhere that connect it.
到处都是连接鞋子的线条。
So it's very open.
所以它非常开放。
It's made of many different thin pieces.
它由很多不同的薄片组成。
Okay, good.
好的，不错。
So we have a strappy sandal, basically a sandal with many straps.
所以我们有绑带凉鞋，基本上就是有很多带子的凉鞋。
And well, she went on to describe sleek high heels.
然后她接着描述了时尚的高跟鞋。
So this is a two-part thing here.
这里有两部分内容。
Sleek is an adjective which basically means really cool looking.
“时尚”是一个形容词，基本上意思是看起来很酷。
Or more like it's pretty and fancy.
或者更准确地说，是漂亮又花哨。
Usually sleek things are also kind of simple, like a Jaguar is a very sleek car.
通常时尚的东西也比较简洁，比如捷豹车就是一款非常时尚的车。
And so this is the adjective to describe the high heels.
所以这是用来描述高跟鞋的形容词。
So we have high heels.
我们有高跟鞋。
We have high heels that are kind of fancy shoe.
我们有那种比较花哨的高跟鞋。
Basically these are shoes that are not flat.
基本上这些鞋不是平底的。
So the heel is very tall.
所以鞋跟很高。
That's right.
没错。
So basically this is what a lot of women wear with dresses.
所以基本上很多女性穿裙子时会穿这种鞋。
Basically the heel has a piece that kind of sticks out and makes the woman look taller.
基本上鞋跟有一块突出的部分，让女性看起来更高。
So basically it's like they're walking on the tips of their toes the entire time.
所以基本上她们就像一直踮着脚尖走路。
Right, and they make click, clack, click, clack.
对，它们会发出咔嗒、咔嗒的声音。
They make that sound.
它们会发出那种声音。
But there are different kinds of heels.
但鞋跟有不同的种类。
High heels obviously means that they're tall.
高跟鞋显然意味着鞋跟很高。
You can have low heels too.
也有低跟鞋。
Those are shorter.
那些比较矮。
But high heels, there are different kinds.
但高跟鞋有不同的种类。
One kind is pumps.
一种是浅口高跟鞋。
Pumps, okay.
浅口高跟鞋，好的。
In the dialer we actually saw the salesman describe them as edgy pumps.
在对话中，我们实际上看到销售员把它们描述为前卫的浅口高跟鞋。
So edgy, what does edgy mean?
那么“前卫”是什么意思呢？
Edgy means cool or hip.
“前卫”意思是酷或时髦。
So young people like to wear edgy clothes, like rock and roll kind of clothes.
所以年轻人喜欢穿前卫的衣服，比如摇滚风格的衣服。
Not so much older people.
不太适合年纪大的人。
And pumps are a type of high heel you say, but what is the difference?
你说浅口高跟鞋是一种高跟鞋，但区别是什么呢？
Well pumps basically are the kind of simple heel that a woman will wear with a pantsuit
嗯，浅口高跟鞋基本上是一种简单的鞋跟，女性会搭配裤装
or with a skirt to the office.
或裙子穿去办公室。
And so they usually have a closed toe and they're quite simple heels.
所以它们通常有封闭的鞋头，而且鞋跟很简单。
Okay.
好的。
And the opposite or maybe a little bit different from pumps would be stilettos.
与浅口高跟鞋相反或略有不同的是细高跟鞋。
So stilettos are a very special kind of heel.
所以细高跟鞋是一种非常特殊的鞋跟。
Stiletto.
细高跟鞋。
It refers basically to the difference in the back of the shoe where you have the heel.
它基本上指的是鞋子后跟部分的区别。
Because sometimes heels are kind of thick and heavy and they make the clunk, clunk sound.
因为有时鞋跟又粗又重，会发出咚咚的声音。
And stilettos are very, very, very thin and very, very tall.
而细高跟鞋非常非常细，而且非常非常高。
Okay.
好的。
So stiletto heels.
所以是细高跟。
I think it's probably easier to walk with pumps rather than stilettos, right?
我觉得穿浅口高跟鞋可能比穿细高跟鞋更容易走路，对吧？
Stilettos are famous for being very, very hard to walk in.
细高跟鞋以非常难走路而闻名。
It's almost like the back of your heel is a chopstick.
几乎就像你的脚后跟是一根筷子。
Wow.
哇。
I cannot imagine doing that.
我无法想象那样走路。
Alright.
好了。
So this is the classification of our high heels.
这就是我们高跟鞋的分类。
Why don't we move on now to Mary Janes.
那我们接下来聊聊玛丽珍鞋吧。
Okay.
好的。
So we've got high heels and heels.
我们聊了高跟鞋和鞋跟。
We also have flats.
我们还有平底鞋。
These are flat shoes.
这些是平底鞋。
So one important kind of flats is a Mary Jane.
所以一种重要的平底鞋是玛丽珍鞋。
Sounds a good name.
听起来是个好名字。
Yeah, it is a name, right?
是啊，它是个名字，对吧？
Mary Jane.
玛丽珍。
So what type of shoe is this?
那这是什么类型的鞋呢？
This is basically a, usually a leather shoe, but it can be different materials.
这基本上是一种通常用皮革做的鞋，但也可以用不同材料。
And it's round in the front and it has one strap and they're very cute.
它前面是圆的，有一条带子，而且非常可爱。
Okay.
好的。
Usually little girls wear Mary Janes, but they're pretty popular these days with older
通常小女孩穿玛丽珍鞋，但现在大人们也很流行穿这个。
people too.
人们也是。
Ah, okay.
啊，好的。
Okay.
好的。
So they're round in the front.
所以它们前面是圆的。
They are usually black and they have one little strap that goes over the top of your foot.
它们通常是黑色的，脚背上有一条小带子。
Mary Janes.
玛丽珍鞋。
Okay.
好的。
Alright.
So we've taken a look at Mary Janes.
所以我们看过了玛丽珍鞋。
Now moving on to, I think it's a similar type of shoe, ballerina shoes.
现在来看，我觉得这是一种类似的鞋子——芭蕾平底鞋。
Well, ballerina shoes are similar because they're flat, but that's about it.
嗯，芭蕾舞鞋之所以类似，是因为它们都是平底的，但也就仅此而已了。
Ballerina shoes are very, very thin.
芭蕾舞鞋非常非常薄。
They're very, very weak.
他们非常非常虚弱。
And usually they're pretty simple.
而且通常它们都很简单。
They're pink or white or black and they're almost like a slipper.
它们是粉色的、白色的或黑色的，几乎像拖鞋一样。
Okay.
好的。
So they don't have the strap on top.
所以它们上面没有那个带子。
No, they're stretchy and you just slide them onto your foot.
不，它们是有弹性的，你直接套在脚上就行。
It's named after dancers, ballerinas, you know, the dancers who wear pink and they put
它的名字来源于舞者，芭蕾舞演员，你知道的，那些穿着粉色衣服的舞者，她们把……
their hair up and they spin around and they're not hard on the bottom.
她们把头发盘起来，然后旋转，鞋底并不硬。
They're usually quite soft and they're always flat.
通常很软，而且总是平底的。
So maybe these ballerina shoes, they're not the specific types of shoes for dancing if
所以这些芭蕾舞鞋，可能并不是芭蕾舞者跳舞时穿的特定鞋款，
you're a ballerina.
如果你是芭蕾舞者的话。
But maybe they're more adequate for maybe walking around the house or something.
但也许它们更适合在家里走动之类的。
You don't really go out hiking with ballerina shoes.
你不会真的穿着芭蕾舞鞋去远足。
No, you don't go out hiking, but they're very popular to wear now to school or work.
不，你不会去远足，但现在穿去上学或上班很流行。
Okay.
好的。
And the other type of shoes that we had, actually this was really confusing to me, slingbacks.
另一种我们提到的鞋子，其实让我很困惑，就是露跟凉鞋。
Slingback shoes.
露跟凉鞋。
Well, slingbacks can be hard because they can be heels, they could be pumps, but it
嗯，露跟凉鞋可能有点复杂，因为它们可以是高跟鞋，也可以是浅口鞋，但
basically refers to a part of the shoe.
它基本上指的是鞋子的一部分。
So normal shoes, they cover the back of your foot, but slingbacks have one strap in the
普通鞋子会包住脚后跟，但露跟凉鞋在后面只有一根带子。
back.
后面。
So maybe if I look at my foot in a slingback, I can see part of my heel.
所以如果我穿着露跟凉鞋看自己的脚，我能看到部分脚后跟。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So slingbacks have a little strap on the back of your heel since the shoe doesn't close
所以露跟凉鞋在脚后跟处有一根小带子，因为鞋子后面不封闭。
in the back.
后面不封闭。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
But you also have high heels and women's shoes that don't close in the back, but that you
但你也有高跟鞋和后面不封闭的女鞋，而且后面也没有带子，对吧？
don't have a strap in the back either, right?
后面也没有带子，对吧？
Those are open shoes.
那些是露跟鞋。
So yeah, they're open in the back, but a slingback, there's one strap that keeps your shoe on.
所以，是的，它们后面是露着的，但如果是后系带鞋，会有一条带子固定住鞋子。
Okay.
好的。
A lot of different types of shoes we've just taken a look at.
我们刚刚看了很多不同类型的鞋子。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back shortly with Fluency
我们不如回去再听一遍对话，稍后我们会回来继续“流利度
Builder.
提升”环节。
Hi, excuse me, sir.
你好，打扰一下，先生。
I'm looking for a dress shoe.
我在找一双正装鞋。
My usual pair that I've had for years have finally been stretched out of shape.
我穿了好几年的那双鞋终于变形了。
They don't provide any support anymore.
它们不再提供任何支撑了。
Sure.
好的。
What kind of shoe are you looking for?
您想找什么样的鞋子？
We've got strappy sandals, sleek high heels, edgy pumps.
我们有系带凉鞋、时尚高跟鞋、前卫浅口鞋。
If you're looking for something a little more practical, we've got Mary Janes, ballerinas.
如果您想要更实用一点的，我们有玛丽珍鞋、芭蕾平底鞋。
Show me some classic high heels, please.
请给我看一些经典高跟鞋。
Okay.
好的。
Right this way.
这边请。
What color did you have in mind?
你想要什么颜色？
Black.
黑色。
Classic.
经典款。
Of course.
当然。
We've got this style here that is very popular.
我们这里有这款非常流行的样式。
Because it's an open toe shoe, you can wear it any time of the year.
因为是露趾鞋，一年四季都能穿。
They look great on everyone.
谁穿都好看。
Um, too shiny.
嗯，太亮了。
And I wear pantyhose with my shoes, so let's look for a closed toe shoe.
而且我穿鞋会配连裤袜，所以还是找双包趾鞋吧。
Okay.
好的。
These are a very nice pair of leather shoes with a two-inch heel, so they are very comfortable.
这双皮鞋很不错，两英寸的鞋跟，穿着很舒服。
I don't like the pointed toes.
我不喜欢尖头。
Let me take a look at what else you have.
让我看看你们还有什么别的款式。
Too high.
太高了。
That one looks like the back would cut into my heel.
那双看起来鞋后跟会磨我的脚后跟。
I have a high instep, so I doubt that one would fit properly.
我脚背高，所以那双恐怕不合脚。
I don't want bows.
我不想要蝴蝶结。
I find slingbacks very uncomfortable.
我觉得露跟凉鞋很不舒服。
Those might as well be stilettos.
那双跟细高跟没两样。
Too modern.
太现代了。
Ah, finally!
啊，终于找到了！
This is what I'm looking for.
这就是我要找的。
What size?
多大码？
Seven and a half.
七码半。
Here we are!
找到了！
How does it fit?
穿着合脚吗？
Hmm, not good.
嗯，不太好。
They're too tight.
太紧了。
The length is right, but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching my toes.
长度合适，但鞋子太窄，夹脚趾。
And there'd be no room for my insoles.
而且也没地方放我的鞋垫。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I don't think I have the patience for this today.
我觉得我今天没耐心折腾了。
They just don't make shoes like they used to.
现在的鞋子就是不如以前做得好。
I'll come back another time.
我改天再来吧。
Have a nice day, ma'am.
祝您愉快，女士。
Alright, we're back, so now let's take a look at five key things on Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看“流利度构建”中的五个关键点。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay, well the reason we're shopping today is because the woman needs a new pair of shoes
好的，我们今天购物的原因是这位女士需要一双新鞋，
because her old shoes can't be worn anymore.
因为她的旧鞋不能再穿了。
What's wrong with them, Marco?
它们怎么了，马可？
She said that they were stretched out of shape.
她说它们穿得变形了。
Okay, so to stretch or to be stretched out, this means that maybe they've been pulled
好的，所以“stretch”或“be stretched out”，意思是它们可能被拉扯
and worn and they're stretched so much that they don't have the original shape anymore.
和穿着，拉伸得太多，以至于失去了原来的形状。
Right.
对。
So just imagine you have a new t-shirt and all of a sudden somebody takes you from your
想象一下你有一件新T恤，突然有人抓住你的
t-shirt and pulls you really hard.
T恤使劲拉你。
And usually what happens is this t-shirt is going to be stretched out of shape.
通常会发生的是这件T恤会被拉得变形。
You pulled it so hard that it loses its original form.
你拉得太用力，它失去了原来的形状。
So now maybe the neck is very low or the t-shirt is too long on one side.
所以可能领口变得很低，或者T恤一边太长。
So that's what happens when you stretch something out of shape.
这就是你把东西拉得变形的情况。
Great.
很好。
So her old shoes are stretched out of shape and they don't provide support anymore.
所以她的旧鞋穿得变形了，不再提供支撑。
So to provide support.
所以“提供支撑”。
Now what kind of support is she referring to?
她指的是什么样的支撑？
She's talking about foot support.
她说的是脚部支撑。
So for example, slippers are a kind of shoe basically that don't provide support.
比如，拖鞋是一种基本上不提供支撑的鞋子。
They're very soft.
它们很软。
But can you walk around all day in slippers?
但你能整天穿着拖鞋走路吗？
No.
不能。
It doesn't help your foot.
它对脚没有帮助。
But if you're trying to find shoes that are really good for walking, you need to find
但如果你想找一双适合走路的鞋，你需要找到
ones that provide support.
提供支撑的鞋子。
That means that always support your foot, the bottom of your foot.
这意味着它们始终支撑你的脚，脚底。
Otherwise your foot gets too tired.
否则你的脚会太累。
Not only the bottom but it could be also your ankle.
不仅是脚底，也可能是脚踝。
For example, you can't really go hiking with shoes like these with sandals because obviously
比如，你不能穿着凉鞋这样的鞋去远足，因为显然
you're walking around rocks and it doesn't provide support on your ankle.
你在岩石上走，它不提供脚踝支撑。
Maybe you can hurt your ankle if you don't have it.
如果没有支撑，你可能会伤到脚踝。
So maybe a hiking boot will provide more support.
所以登山靴可能会提供更多支撑。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright.
好的。
And then the woman also mentioned that it's hard for her to find a shoe because she said
然后这位女士还提到她很难找到合适的鞋，因为她说
I have a high instep.
“我的脚背高”。
Okay so think about the foot.
好的，想想脚。
You've got toes in the very front and a heel in the very back but in the middle on top
前面有脚趾，后面有脚跟，但中间顶部
you have the instep.
是脚背。
So this is basically the top of your foot.
所以这基本上是脚的顶部。
Okay.
好的。
So if she has a high instep, it means that her foot is kind of thick.
所以如果她脚背高，意味着她的脚有点厚。
That's right.
没错。
Some people have thin feet.
有些人脚薄。
She has kind of a thick foot.
她的脚有点厚。
So fitting her foot into a shoe is sometimes hard.
所以把脚塞进鞋里有时很难。
Right.
对。
We're not talking about the width of the foot.
我们不是在说脚的宽度。
We're talking about the height.
我们在说高度。
Like how tall.
比如多高。
How tall it is.
它有多高。
From the bottom to the top of the foot.
从脚底到脚顶。
Right.
对。
So that's what she means by high instep.
这就是她说的“高脚背”的意思。
And well they also mentioned different types of shoes.
而且他们还提到了不同类型的鞋子。
She said she didn't want an open toe shoe.
她说她不想要露趾鞋。
She wanted a closed toe shoe.
她想要包趾鞋。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a really important classification for women's shoes especially.
这对女鞋来说尤其是一个重要的分类。
Open toe means that the toe of the shoe, the very very front, has a hole or an opening.
“露趾”意味着鞋头，最前面，有一个洞或开口。
So you can see the toes.
所以你能看到脚趾。
Right.
对。
Closed toe is the opposite.
“包趾”则相反。
So personally in the winter time I always wear closed toed shoes because I think open
所以冬天的时候，我一般都穿包趾鞋，因为我觉得露趾鞋太冷了。
toe shoes are too cold.
太冷了。
Too cold.
Okay.
好吧。
So that's basically it.
基本上就是这样。
I guess men, we don't really have this type of shoe between open toe and closed toe.
我觉得男人吧，我们其实没有这种介于露趾和包趾之间的鞋。
No.
没有。
Maybe.
也许吧。
No.
没有。
You don't really.
确实没有。
But heels maybe you could have an open toe.
但高跟鞋的话，也许可以有露趾的。
You can have an open toe shoe or closed toed shoe.
你可以有露趾鞋或者包趾鞋。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好吧。
So a lot of interesting things.
所以有很多有趣的东西。
This is useful for women out there and also for boyfriends.
这对女士们很有用，对男朋友们也很有用。
Maybe now you know what type of shoe your girlfriend may want.
也许现在你知道你女朋友可能想要什么类型的鞋了。
That's right.
没错。
Alright.
好了。
So we're going to listen to this dialogue for the last time and we'll be back shortly.
那我们最后再听一遍这段对话，一会儿就回来。
Hi.
嗨。
Excuse me, sir.
打扰一下，先生。
I'm looking for a dress shoe.
我在找一双正装鞋。
My usual pair that I've had for years have finally been stretched out of shape.
我穿了好多年的那双鞋终于变形了。
They don't provide any support anymore.
它们不再提供任何支撑了。
Sure.
当然。
What kind of shoe are you looking for?
你在找什么样的鞋？
We've got strappy sandals, sleek high heels, edgy pumps.
我们有绑带凉鞋、时尚高跟鞋、前卫的浅口鞋。
If you're looking for something a little more practical, we've got Mary Janes, ballerinas.
如果你想要更实用一点的，我们有玛丽珍鞋、芭蕾平底鞋。
Show me some classic high heels, please.
请给我看一些经典的高跟鞋。
Okay.
好的。
Right this way.
这边请。
What color did you have in mind?
你想要什么颜色？
Black.
黑色。
Classic.
经典。
Of course.
当然。
We've got this style here that is very popular.
我们这里有这款很流行的。
Because it's an open toe shoe, you can wear it any time of the year.
因为是露趾鞋，一年四季都能穿。
They look great on everyone.
谁穿都好看。
Too shiny.
太亮了。
And I wear pantyhose with my shoes.
而且我穿鞋会配连裤袜。
So let's look for a closed toe shoe.
所以还是找包趾鞋吧。
Okay.
好的。
These are a very nice pair of leather shoes with a two-inch heel.
这双皮鞋很不错，有两英寸的跟。
So they are very comfortable.
所以穿起来很舒服。
I don't like the pointed toes.
我不喜欢尖头。
Let me take a look at what else you have.
让我看看你们还有什么别的。
Too high.
太高了。
That one looks like the back would cut into my heel.
那双看起来后跟会磨我的脚后跟。
I have a high instep, so I doubt that one would fit properly.
我脚背高，所以我觉得那双可能不合脚。
I don't want bows.
我不想要蝴蝶结。
I find slingbacks very uncomfortable.
我觉得露跟凉鞋很不舒服。
Those might as well be stilettos.
那双跟细高跟也差不多了。
Too modern.
太现代了。
Ah, finally!
啊，终于找到了！
This is what I'm looking for.
这就是我要找的。
What size?
什么尺码？
Seven and a half.
七码半。
Here we are.
给你。
How does it fit?
合脚吗？
Not good.
不好。
They're too tight.
太紧了。
The length is right, but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching my toes.
长度合适，但鞋太窄了，夹我的脚趾。
And there'd be no room for my insoles.
而且也没地方放我的鞋垫。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I don't think I have the patience for this today.
我觉得我今天没耐心折腾这个了。
They just don't make shoes like they used to.
他们就是不像以前那样做鞋了。
I'll come back another time.
我改天再来。
Have a nice day, ma'am.
祝您愉快，女士。
All right, so talking about shoes, there are so many types and I think women are notoriously
好了，说到鞋子，种类真多，我觉得女人以鞋子多而闻名。
famous for having a lot of shoes.
以鞋子多而闻名。
Why is this?
这是为什么？
Some women are.
有些女人是这样。
Some women aren't.
有些女人不是。
It depends on the person.
这要看人。
Part of the problem, as you said earlier, is that there are so many different kinds
部分问题，就像你之前说的，是女鞋种类太多了，以至于现在我们期望女人为每种不同场合都准备一双不同的鞋。
of women's shoes that now we expect women to have a different pair of shoes for every
女鞋种类太多了，以至于现在我们期望女人为每种不同场合都准备一双不同的鞋。
different occasion.
不同的场合。
Work shoes, hiking shoes, running shoes, wedding shoes, summer shoes, winter shoes, fall shoes.
工作鞋、徒步鞋、跑鞋、婚礼鞋、夏天鞋、冬天鞋、秋天鞋。
You need so many different kinds of shoes, you end up buying many different kinds.
你需要这么多不同种类的鞋子，结果就买了很多种。
I think that's true.
我觉得确实如此。
Also basically, women like to look nice.
而且基本上，女人喜欢打扮得好看。
That's why you do your makeup, you have earrings, and they have nice bags.
这就是为什么你化妆、戴耳环，还有漂亮的包包。
So I guess it's also part of it is that you pay more attention to what type of shoe you're
所以我想这也是其中一部分，你会更注意穿什么类型的鞋子，
wearing that maybe goes well with the outfit.
才能和衣服搭配得好。
I think maybe guys, not all guys obviously as well as not all women, but guys are a little
我觉得男人，当然不是所有男人，就像不是所有女人一样，但男人有点
bit more generic.
更随意一些。
It's like jeans pretty much go well with any type of shoe as long as it's maybe black or
就像牛仔裤基本上和任何鞋子都搭配，只要鞋子是黑色或
brown or something like this.
棕色之类的。
True.
没错。
Although I know a lot of guys who have many different kinds of shoes.
虽然我认识很多男人也有各种不同的鞋子。
True.
没错。
It takes up a lot of space in the closet as well.
这也占了很多衣柜空间。
It does.
确实。
Shoes are hard to carry around.
鞋子很难携带。
And actually I find it kind of hard to get rid of my shoes.
而且我发现我很难扔掉我的鞋子。
I think they have to be ripped or just completely unwearable in order for me to throw a shoe
我觉得它们必须得破了或者完全不能穿了，我才会把一双鞋
away because otherwise you can still wear it sometimes on the weekend.
扔掉，因为不然的话，你周末还能穿穿。
That's true.
没错。
Although I tend to wear my shoes down.
虽然我倾向于把鞋子穿到坏。
That means I wear them until they die.
就是说我一直穿到它们报废。
Really?
真的吗？
And then I throw them away.
然后我就扔掉它们。
Actually I've had shoes that I've worn the soles down and then I just get the sole changed
其实我有过一些鞋子，我把鞋底磨穿了，然后我就去换鞋底，
because I like the shoe so much.
因为我太喜欢那双鞋了。
Well, let us know.
好了，告诉我们吧。
Do you guys like to buy shoes?
你们喜欢买鞋吗？
Do you have a lot of shoes?
你们有很多鞋吗？
Maybe you don't have that many shoes.
也许你没有那么多鞋。
We're curious to know about this in other cultures as well because I know in the States,
我们也很好奇其他文化的情况，因为我知道在美国，
in the United States, shoe shopping is very, very popular.
在美国，买鞋非常非常流行。
In Holland they have traditional wooden shoes.
在荷兰，他们有传统的木鞋。
Yeah, they do.
是的，他们有。
Those are called clogs.
那些叫做木屐。
Clogs.
木屐。
So let us know maybe what type of shoes are also very unique to your country or culture.
所以告诉我们，也许你们国家或文化中有什么独特的鞋子。
We're at EnglishPod.com.
我们在EnglishPod.com。
We'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。